JEREMY BARBER

Web developer (1+ year) with a background in IT (2 years), sales (2 years) and intelligence operations (3.5 years). Experienced in designing and developing user interfaces, RESTful APIs, databases, and responsive websites. Proven ability to convert requirements into software and improve workflow.

CONTACT

- jeremydev2020@gmail.com
- **** 702-569-2155
- Las Vegas, Nevada
- unlimitedcode.dev
- O @onlytruejeremy
- in Jeremy Barber

SKILLS

Programming

Front End:

HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, ReactJS, JSON, Formik, Yup

Middle Tier:

NodeJS, ExpressJS, Joi, JWT, BCRYPT, CORS, Helmet

Back End:

SQL, MongoDB, FireBase

ΙT

Networking

Configure, support and maintain network infrastructure

Cybersecurity

Risk management, Threat analysis and prevention

Soft Skills

Customer Relations

Communication, CRM Tools, Relationship Building, Sales

Analysis

Research, Critical Thinking, Problem Solving

EDUCATION

- Security+, CompTIA 2018
- GEOINT Professional Certification, NGA 2018
- Intelligence Operations, Cochise College 2016

WORK HISTORY

m Dec 2020 - Current

V NET, Las Vegas IT Technician

- Diagnosed, troubleshot and resolved a range of software, hardware and connectivity issues. Excelled in inquiring about complications, researching, analyzing and rectifying problems which improved quality of service, reduced client attrition and led to being employee of the month runner up.
- Converted dozens of residents into clients increasing yearly revenue by over \$25,000 within two months.
- Created and managed accounts for clientele ensuring the ability to make payments and file trouble tickets through their online portals.

1 01/2020 - 12/2020

♀ WebMall, Las Angeles

Full Stack Developer

- Converted business requirements into RESTful services for orders, invoices and discount features of the application using NodeJS and MSSQL. Integrated RESTful services in ReactJS components with role guards and conditional rendering in place for identity and access management.
- Refactored code to prevent SQL injection attacks by implementing form and data validation with Formik, Yup and Joi in ReactJS and NodeJS respectively.
- Performed peer code reviews with other developers in an agile environment to resolve bugs and merge new features using Git into the repository, preventing erroneous code from disrupting performance of the application.
- Utilized CSS Flexbox and media queries, enhancing user experience by making the layout of the pages mobile responsive.

🛗 Jan 2020 - May 2020

American Income

Benefits Advisor

- Performed outbound calls, met with prospective customers and presented information related to available services resulting in the conversion of dozens of residents into clients.
- Outreached to lapsed policy owners and re-enrolled them into benefit programs, increasing customer retention.
- Assisted clients with completion of appropriate forms, scheduling necessary medical examinations, fulfilling legal and regulatory requirements.

Mar 2016 - Dec 2019

♀ U.S. Army.

GEOINT Analyst

- Earned an Army Commendation Medal for optimizing workflow, resolving hardware and software related issues, and assisting multiple commanders' decision making within three combatant commands through the exploitation of Full Motion Video.
- Established and encrypted communication channels, resolved connectivity and software issues in RHEL7, Windows and those involving radio devices for which two Army Achievement Medals were received.
- Collected over 3000 data points and produced a quantitative and qualitative assessment for a pilot program under the Joint Artificial Intelligence Center, used by key decision makers to improve the functionality of Al.
- Created macros in excel that optimized workflow, enabled quick collation of data and analysis, reduced analyst burden and decreased product creation time by over 30%.
- Produced a continuity book with instructional guides for incoming analysts mitigating time spent on-boarding and training personnel by several weeks.